Guide to the Clifford J. Earle papers, 1953-2011.
Earle, Clifford J. papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Clifford J. Earle papers, 1953-2011.
14-19-4339
Clifford John, Jr. Earle
4 cubic feet.
Correspondence, diaries, research material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection includes course material, correspondence, diaries, papers and other miscellaneous notes.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Clifford's research concerned invariants belonging to Riemann surfaces. He earned his Bachelor's degree from Swarthmore in 1957 and his Master's and Ph.D. degrees from Harvard in 1958 and in 1962 under the direction of Lars Ahlfors. His thesis was titled Teichmuand#x308;ller Spaces of Groups of the Second Kind. A paper of the same title was published in Acta Mathematica in 1964. From 1963 to 1965 he was a member of the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton. In 1965 he became an Assistant Professor and in 1969 Full Professor at Cornell. From 1976 to 1979 he served as Chair of Mathematics. He was the first member of the Department to serve on the newly formed Faculty Senate in 1969. Cliff was a Guggenheim Fellow, an inaugural Fellow of the American Mathematical Society, a Distinguished Ordway Visitor at the University of Minnesota and Honorary Professor at the University of Warwick.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes course material, correspondence, diaries, papers and other miscellaneous notes.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Earle, Clifford John, Jr.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Course Material
Series II. General Documents
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Course Material
  - Math 422 Notes, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Math 711 Notes, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Math 612 Notes, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Math 112 Old Tests and Notes, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Math 422 Notes, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Math 612 Notes, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Math 712 Notes, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Math 514 Notes, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Math 622 Notes, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - R. Kuhnau Papers, 1988-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Analysis Seminar, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Math 612 Notes, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Math 622 Notes, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Math 622 Notes, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Math 622 Notes, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Exams, 1957-1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Homework Sets, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Math 222 Notes, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Classroom Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - HRI Book Chapter, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Series II. General Documents
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Correspondence- M, 1998-2001 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Correspondence- M - N, 1976-1999 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Correspondence- Nag, 1986-1999 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Correspondence- O-Q, 1996-2005 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Correspondence- S, 1983-2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Correspondence- S-V, 1984-1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Correspondence- W, 1981-2004 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Correspondence- XYZ, 1974-1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Reprints and Papers, 1964-1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Reprints and Papers, 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Reprints and Papers, 1985-1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Reprints and Papers, 1994-1998 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Reprints and Papers, 2000-2011 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Techmuller Spaces of Groups of the Second Kind, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Photos, 1953-1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Obituary Items, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Clifford Earle CV and Bibliography, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Clifford Earle's College Career, 1953-1957 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- A, 1964-2017 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- B, 1967-2003 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- C-D, 1971-2002 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- E-F, 1969-2001 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- F-G, 1967-1997 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- H, 1968-1996 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- I, 1974-2009 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- J, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Jerusalem Conference Notes, 1995-1999 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- K, 1971-1999 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- Kra, 1972-1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- L, 1961-2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- M, 1987-2006 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- M, 1970-1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence- Marden, 1970-1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Photos and Publications, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Notebook, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - NSF Hawaiian Conference Materials, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Larry Harris Project, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1998-2002 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Quotient Maps (Nonsplit Submersions), 2002 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Contraction in AT (AT2), 2002 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Contraction Inequalities (General Case), 2000 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Holo Tech Contraction and Conformal Radius, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - C1 Example and Gaier Paper, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - AT1 and LVA for AB98, 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Chile Paper, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - EGL Zygmund Papers, 1997-08-21 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Bers Volume Paper, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Embedded Polydisks Papers, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Teichmuller Disks- Affine View Papers, 1997-2004 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Isometry Stuff with FPG, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Families over Punctured Disk Notes, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Actor Modular Gp Hausduff Quotient, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1/2- Canonical Divisors Papers, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Sections of Tech Curve over T(1,m) and Other Genus 1 Material, Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Stuff, Undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Diaries, 1977-2009 (Box 4)